<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Place to Remember</title>
    <link>https://renodesper.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Place to Remember</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://renodesper.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey to Functional Programming</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-12-11-journey-to-functional-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-12-11-journey-to-functional-programming/</guid>
      <description>Dulu, dulu sekali. Saya pernah mencari tentang apa saja hal yang harus saya pelajari agar saya bisa lebih ahli dalam pemrograman Python. Lalu secara tidak sengaja saya menemukan jawaban di stackoverflow yang menyarankan untuk membaca buku Real World Haskell. Di sinilah perjalanan saya menuju Functional Programming dimulai. And the journey begin~
Saya sempat mempelajari Scala di tempat saya bekerja, hanya saja saat itu pekerjaan saya dipindahkan kembali ke pekerjaan yang menggunakan bahasa Python sehingga saya tidak terlalu dalam mempelajari Scala.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maven Dependency Problem</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-09-15-maven-dependency-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-09-15-maven-dependency-problem/</guid>
      <description>I have a problem downloading several pom files from local artifactory. Well, those poms literally doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist but the jar files are there, so it should not be a problem. The weird thing is it failed to build the package with maven.
So, I create those poms manually. And when I try to build it again:
$ mvn package  The log said:
 [WARNING] The POM for &amp;ldquo;package&amp;rdquo; is invalid, transitive dependencies (if any) will not be available, enable debug logging for more details</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Default Browser</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-04-12-set-default-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-04-12-set-default-browser/</guid>
      <description>For a few month after I did a fresh install of Archlinux, I found that when I try to click a link inside any application, it will call google chrome. So, I decide to fix it today. It actually easy. We can set our default browser with xdg-mime which is owned by xdg-utils.
Requirement  xdg-utils  What I did We can set out default browser with these commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Gif from Video as Project Demo</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-02-21-create-gif-from-video-for-project-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-02-21-create-gif-from-video-for-project-demo/</guid>
      <description>This time I will show you how to make a gif from a video. Why do we need this? Well, a few hours ago I need to create a demo of a program to get a job. But I can&amp;rsquo;t give them the source code, that&amp;rsquo;s why I just show them how the program works.
Requirement  Simple Screen Recorder / similar software ffmpeg  What I did The first thing we need to do is create a video with Simple Screen Recorder / similar software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dive into Sqlite</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-02-19-dive-into-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2016-02-19-dive-into-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Today we will talk about sqlite in python. I often use mysql as my data source because of a habit, but when I am in a hurry, I guess sqlite will be enough.
To keep in mind:  I use python3 Sqlite library is called sqlite3 I use hashlib to hash the password (not required)  Action Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a little bit of code:
#!/usr/bin/python # -*- coding: utf-8 -*- import hashlib import sqlite3 con = sqlite3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berbagi Buku</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-10-04-berbagi-buku/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-10-04-berbagi-buku/</guid>
      <description>Prakata Salam,
Kebetulan ada beberapa buku yang sudah jarang saya baca. Oleh karena itu, daripada hanya memenuhi ruangan kosan saya, sepertinya akan lebih baik untuk diberikan kepada yang membutuhkan. Membutuhkan di sini bukan berarti &amp;ldquo;dibaca jika sedang mood&amp;rdquo; tapi lebih ke membutuhkan karena memang ingin membaca / menggunakan buku tersebut. Harapan saya, jika misalnya buku-buku tersebut sudah tidak dibutuhkan lagi nantinya, maka akan lebih baik jika buku tersebut diberikan lagi kepada orang lain oleh orang yang meminjam sebelumnya, semacam chain reaction gitu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Time with Awk</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-07-30-my-first-time-with-awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-07-30-my-first-time-with-awk/</guid>
      <description>Tonight we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about Awk. Actually, I&amp;rsquo;ve know it for a long time but I never had any chance to explore it. A few days ago, I need to remove some duplicate lines from a file BUT it should not be sorted. We can also use sort and uniq, but it will end up sorted before we got an actual result. I&amp;rsquo;m using this kind of script to remove it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Screen in Detach Mode</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-07-12-starting-screen-in-detach-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-07-12-starting-screen-in-detach-mode/</guid>
      <description>For a few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about GNU/screen. I have some scripts that should be run inside screen everytime a reboot happened. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking in stackoverflow, google, etc but haven&amp;rsquo;t found anything useful. So I&amp;rsquo;ve been stuck with this kind of script:
$ screen -dmS screen_name some_command  It will create a new screen, run the command inside it and detach the screen. Well, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good actually. But, when the command is done (finished or killed) then the screen will be terminated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django Project</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-06-13-django-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-06-13-django-project/</guid>
      <description>For about a month I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy building a Django project. Even though everyday I work with python, but I never try any framework like Django. I can not say it&amp;rsquo;s hard, but with all those &amp;ldquo;jobs&amp;rdquo; in my office, this month is the busiest time for me to took another project (I never know that I will be this busy). Deadline is in the corner and the project is about 75%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untracking The Tracked Ones</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-06-13-untracking-the-tracked-ones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-06-13-untracking-the-tracked-ones/</guid>
      <description>Sudah beberapa hari saya mempunyai keinginan untuk memperbaiki projek yang saya lakukan. Secara tidak sengaja saya memasukkan virtual environment ke dalam repositori yang notabene seharusnya hanya diisi oleh projek yang saya kerjakan. Alhasil banyak sekali perubahan setiap saya mencoba mengerjakan kembali (bahkan) ketika saya tidak mengubah apapun.
Berikut cara yang saya temukan untuk meng-untrack file / folder yang sudah di-track:
$ git rm --cached -r env  Setelah itu, folder tersebut bisa kita masukkan ke dalam file .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-06-04-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-06-04-migration/</guid>
      <description>Jadi begini, rencananya saya menggunakan Ghost sebagai blog adalah untuk belajar NodeJS. Sayangnya saya selalu sibuk dan tidak sempat untuk mempelajari NodeJS sekalipun. Akhirnya saya berpikir, daripada membebani server lebih baik saya ubah saja blog-nya ke sesuatu yang lebih ringan. Static site pun muncul di benak saya. Saya menggunakan Hugo untuk men-generate situs ini.
Udah sih gitu aja, saya gitu sih orangnya. B|</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timestamp and Date in Apache Phoenix</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-03-13-timestamp-and-date-in-apache-phoenix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-03-13-timestamp-and-date-in-apache-phoenix/</guid>
      <description>For a several days I&amp;rsquo;ve played with Apache Phoenix. Instead of playing with HBase directly, Phoenix helped me simplify HBase query (well, just a bit). What I want to tell you now is not about Phoenix in general but the difference between Timestamp and Date in Phoenix.
I have 2 column which have different format. I thought that both column should have different data type as well. Those format is like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dvorak programmer&#39;s time</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-01-18-dvorak-programmers-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2015-01-18-dvorak-programmers-time/</guid>
      <description>Jadi begini, beberapa hari belakangan ini saya sedang menikmati belajar menggunakan layout dvorak programmer. Keycode untuk layout tersebut adalah dvp. Jujur saja, sangat sulit untuk menggunakan layout tersebut terlebih lagi jika kita sudah terbiasa menggunakan qwerty. Terkadang jadi jemari saya kembali ke tempat dimana huruf tersebut berada di qwerty. Ini yang saya lakukan agar saya tidak terganggu dengan tampilan keyword qwerty yang ada di laptop saya: dvorak workaround</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editing Stream like Merlin The Mighty with Sed</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-12-18-editing-stream-like-merlin-the-mighty-with-sed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-12-18-editing-stream-like-merlin-the-mighty-with-sed/</guid>
      <description>We already talk about Vim a couple of time. Let&amp;rsquo;s move to sed. Sed is a stream editor (we already know that) that I used today. This is the case, I have some file (php file) which is badly written by someone (maybe for pissing me off) by changing some characters on it. Let&amp;rsquo;s say they change *.php into .rrrr wherever possible. It&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal if the file is only have a few lines, but imagine if it has 2000 lines and I should edit every .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menghapus baris di Vim - 2</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-12-09-menghapus-baris-di-vim-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-12-09-menghapus-baris-di-vim-2/</guid>
      <description>Case Terkadang kita ingin menghapus baris-baris tertentu yang hanya mengandung kata-kata yang spesifik. Contohnya jika ingin menghapus log tetapi menyisakan baris yang mengandung kata warning atau error atau lainnya.
Solution Ada 2 ex command yang dapat kita gunakan yang berhubungan dengan masalah tersebut.
1. :g/{pola yang ingin dicari}/{perintah yang ingin dijalankan setelah pola ditemukan} 2. :v/{pola yang tidak ingin dicari}/{perintah yang ingin dijalankan setelah pola ditemukan}  Example 1. Untuk menghapus setiap baris yang mengandung pola &amp;quot;warning&amp;quot; kita bisa menggunakan: :g/warning/d 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menghapus baris di Vim - 1</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-12-04-menghapus-baris-di-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-12-04-menghapus-baris-di-vim/</guid>
      <description>Case Terkadang kita perlu menghapus beberapa baris secara berurutan dan secara spesifik. Contohnya adalah jika kita ingin menghapus 491 baris dari baris ke 105. Seperti yang kita tahu, kita bisa menggunakan dd untuk menghapus 1 baris di Vim. Tapi bagaimana untuk kasus di atas? Mengutip dari suatu blog, penggunaan Vim itu seperti kita berbahasa (thanks for Daniel Miessler for your awesome post). Caranya seperti berikut:
Solution 1. 491dd = menghapus 491 baris ke bawah dengan syarat posisi kita harus ada di baris 105 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mengurutkan isi file menggunakan Sort</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-11-27-mengurutkan-isi-file-menggunakan-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-11-27-mengurutkan-isi-file-menggunakan-sort/</guid>
      <description>Saya rasa kita semua pernah merasa kesulitan dalam mengurutkan sesuatu. Beberapa waktu yang lalu saya ingin mengurutkan id yang akan saya olah yang sumbernya terdapat dari 2 file. Untuk kasus ini saya menggunakan sort, saya rasa tidak ada yang lebih mudah dari sort untuk melakukan proses ini melalui command line. sort image
Kita bisa menggunakan parameter -m untuk melakukan merging ataupun langsung mengarahkan keluarannya ke file yang lain menggunakan simbol &amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Vim Plugins - 2</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-11-13-my-vim-plugins-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-11-13-my-vim-plugins-2/</guid>
      <description>flazz/vim-colorschemes vim-colorschemes is a collection of colorscheme from vim.org. My favorite is Tomorrow-Night-Eighties which looks like this: Tomorrow-Night-Eighties image
This plugin has a lot of colorschemes, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ever have a chance to try all of it
eiginn/netrw netrw is a must-have plugin if you often connect to remote server. Instead of editing file on the remote server, you can use netrw to do some editing right in vim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New VPS for Node</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-10-15-new-vps-for-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-10-15-new-vps-for-node/</guid>
      <description>Kita skip dulu bahasan tentang Vim yang ada di post sebelumnya. Kemarin saya baru saja menyewa sebuah vps yang nantinya akan saya gunakan untuk riset. VPS tersebut saya pasangkan Centos 7 x86_64. Hal pertama yang saya lakukan adalah memasang nodejs dan npm. Berikut langkah - langkah yang saya lakukan.
Update sistem $ yum update  Instal EPEL (Extra Packages for Enterprise Linux) Repository $ yum install epel-release  Instal Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Vim Plugins - 1</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-10-06-my-vim-plugins-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-10-06-my-vim-plugins-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction First thing first. What is Vim? As far as I can tell, Vim is an imitation of Vi. But tldr it is an improved version of Vi now. The last thing that I remember is Vim is not a word processor, it is an editor. You should find the difference yourself.
So, now I wanna show you all Vim plugins that I used. It’s not much but it really help me a lot when I code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pairing Logitech Devices With Solaar</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-09-18-pairing-logitech-devices-with-solaar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-09-18-pairing-logitech-devices-with-solaar/</guid>
      <description>A few minutes ago, a friend of mine shared something good on facebook. He use Solaar to get battery information from his Logitech mouse. So, what is Solaar?
Quoted from Solaar website:
&amp;quot;Solaar is a Linux device manager for Logitech&#39;s Unifying Receiver peripherals.&amp;quot;  It gives you information about your device&amp;rsquo;s technical detail like Wireless PID, Protocol, Polling Rate, Serial number, even your device&amp;rsquo;s firmware. And of course, it gives battery information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menukar Fungsi Tombol Mouse atau Touchpad</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-09-01-menukar-fungsi-tombol-mouse-atau-touchpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-09-01-menukar-fungsi-tombol-mouse-atau-touchpad/</guid>
      <description>Mungkin ini terdengar aneh, tetapi saya mempunyai kebiasaan untuk menukar fungsi tombol yang ada di mouse walaupun sebetulnya saya bukan left-handed. Untuk menukar fungsi tombol yang ada di mouse kita bisa menggunakan perintah berikut:
$ xmodmap -e &amp;quot;pointer = 3 2 1&amp;quot;  Ada masalah yang muncul jika kita menggunakan perintah di atas. Masalahnya adalah perintah tersebut akan menukar fungsi mouse secara umum, maksudnya adalah touchpad yang juga bisa digunakan selain mouse akan tertukar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grep for The World</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-08-11-grep-for-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-08-11-grep-for-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Pernahkah kalian merasa kesulitan saat ingin mencari sebuah file yang kalian tidak tahu nama file-nya tetapi (sedikit) tahu apa isinya? Untuk mencari file yang misterius seperti ini kita bisa menggunakan grep. Berikut adalah contoh grep yang baru saja saya gunakan:
$ grep -r -i &amp;quot;INSERT INTO news&amp;quot; *.py  Perintah di atas berguna untuk mencari file berakhiran &amp;ldquo;.py&amp;rdquo; yang di dalamnya mengandung kalimat &amp;ldquo;INSERT INTO news&amp;rdquo;. Opsi &amp;ldquo;-r&amp;rdquo; akan membuat grep dapat mencari file tersebut secara rekursif pada folder tersebut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser Tunneling</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-26-browser-tunneling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-26-browser-tunneling/</guid>
      <description>Prolog Okay, we will talk about tunneling. I have a task to do in a few days, I need to remote 3 servers which cannot be accessed from outside of my office. So, I guess I have to use a tunnel. With that being said, this is what I do to achieve that.
Workaround $ ssh -D {port} -N {user}@{tunneled-ip-address} -p {tunneled-port}  Now, if I want to access some specific web page which can only be accessed from my office I only need to change how my browser connect to the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erasing Partition Table</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-21-erasing-partition-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-21-erasing-partition-table/</guid>
      <description>Well, I always use gparted to erase my partition table and sometimes it fail miserably. The most accurate way is to use sgdisk. We can erase our partition table like this:
$ sgdisk --zap-all /dev/sda  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiveReload Integration</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-14-livereload-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-14-livereload-integration/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Apa itu livereload? LiveReload adalah sebuah tool yang dapat kita gunakan untuk melakukan reload (refresh) pada browser sesuai dengan trigger tertentu. Misalnya jika sebuah file disimpan, jika ada sebuah GET request, bahkan kita juga bisa menambahkan delay sebelum reload dijalankan. Lalu hal apa saja yang harus kita lakukan untuk dapat menggunakan livereload? Sublime Text and LiveReload Integration
Oke, ada 2 pilihan server yang bisa kita (saya sudah coba) gunakan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postgresql and Metasploit</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-12-postgresql-and-metasploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-07-12-postgresql-and-metasploit/</guid>
      <description>Dulu saya selalu penasaran bagaimana caranya menggunakan metasploit dan konfigurasi database-nya. Tetapi ternyata selama ini saya hanya kurang paham dengan alurnya. Berikut saya tuliskan apa yang sudah saya pahami saat ini.
First Step Hal pertama yang harus diperhatikan adalah database. Database yang digunakan oleh metasploit adalah postgresql. Setelah memasang postgresql di sistem yang kita miliki, kita harus membuat sebuah database yang nantinya akan digunakan oleh metasploit, begitu juga dengan user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Querying Solr from Python with MySolr</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-05-01-querying-solr-from-python-with-mysolr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-05-01-querying-solr-from-python-with-mysolr/</guid>
      <description>Introduction MySolr is an API for Apache&amp;rsquo;s Solr for python. You can install mysolr using your favorite package manager. In the last post I have showed you how to update, select, and delete index using curl. Today, I will show you how we do those things using mysolr. Basic Configuration
There is nothing special with solr configuration. The first thing you should do is importing Solr from mysolr. If you have done that, you can set the connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play with Apache Solr</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-04-30-play-with-apache-solr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-04-30-play-with-apache-solr/</guid>
      <description>Okay, Solr. It&amp;rsquo;s the first time I play with Solr. I will never know about it if I don&amp;rsquo;t join this company. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with selecting index.
Select We can select an index using this command:
curl http://localhost:8983/solr/{core}/select?q=id:{id}  Insert / Update There are two commands to insert or update index. Just remember, the structure should be identical.
Insert / Update with JSON curl http://localhost:8983/solr/{core}/update?commit=true -H &#39;Content-type:application/json&#39; -d &#39;[ { &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;{id}&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;desc&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;{description}&amp;quot; } ]&#39;  Insert / Update with XML curl http://localhost:8983/solr/{core}/update?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should I learn about Linux</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-04-12-what-should-i-learn-about-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-04-12-what-should-i-learn-about-linux/</guid>
      <description>Okay, for now I want to list everything which I should learn about GNU/Linux in 2 part. Let&amp;rsquo;s say it for the beginner and advance.
Beginner 1. Introduction to GNU/Linux 2. GNU/Linux Desktop Environment 3. Unix Command Line 4. Text Editing Tools 5. Shell Scripting 6. TCP/IP Networking Basics 7. X-Windows 8. Native GNU/Linux Compiler, Software ad Services  Advance 1. Filesystem Management 2. Software Management 3. User and Group Management 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post!</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-04-10-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/post/2014-04-10-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Today, I tried something different. Well, I just want to improve my programming language and english but I don&amp;rsquo;t have any idea about what should I do. And I thought why don&amp;rsquo;t I learn by documenting what I have done. Maybe I will learn more serious to avoid making mistake when I write it.
Here we go, a blog made from ghost with everything about everything. Oh right, I will use 2 different languages in this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://renodesper.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renodesper.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Boy Sandy Gladies Arriezona. I use this site to document what I did or anything that I thought interesting. As a developer, I have the following qualities:
 I use Archlinux (Debian/Centos on server) I use Vim (VS Code when I was lazy) I code in Python and Golang for backend stuff I code in Vue for frontend stuff  My History To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m having some trouble remembering right now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>